Yavapai Cattle Growers papers 1933-1965
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Yavapai Cattle Growers papers, 1933-1965
AZ 023
Yavapai Cattle Growers (Association)
2.1 linear feet
Correspondence, financial records, membership lists, reports, photographs, and other materials relating to the formation of the organization, to its history and activities, and its association with similar state and national groups. Includes similar records of the Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association.
Univerity of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Organized in 1931, the Prescott-based Association's goal was to promote the cattle industry in Yavapai County, Ariz.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Correspondence and Reports, 1933-1965
Series II: Financial Records, 1933-1961
Series III: Calf Sale Records, 1938-1963
Series IV: Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association Records, 1932-1964
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, financial records, membership lists, reports, photographs, and other materials relating to the formation of the organization, to its history and activities, and its association with similar state and national groups. Includes similar records of the Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association. Photographs pertain to calf sales in the 1930s and 1960s; and a scrapbook has photographs of members of the earlier association, 1913, and Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers, 1940s and 1950s.
Access Terms
Arizona Cattle Growers' Association
Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers' Association -- Records and correspondence
Yavapai Cattle Growers (Association) -- Records and correspondence
Cattle trade -- Arizona
Cattle -- Arizona
Cattle breeders -- Arizona -- Yavapai County
Accounts
Albums
Correspondence
Reports
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence and Reports, 1933-1965
  - Correspondence. 1933-1961, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Membership lists. 1940-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Announcements. 1936-1965 (Box 2)
- Series II: Financial Records, 1933-1961
  - Treasurers' reports. 1933-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Valley National Bank: statements, checks. 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bank of Arizona: statements (general account). 1947-1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bank of Arizona & First National Bank of Arizona: statements (general account). 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bank of Arizona: statements (petty cash account). 1947-1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bank of Arizona & First National Bank of Arizona: statements (petty cash account). 1954-1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bank of Arizona: statements, checks (memorial fund). 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bills. 1939-1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Insurance and tax papers. 1941,1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bank of Arizona: check stubbs (general account). 1946-1957 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Bank of Arizona: check stubbs, checks (petty cash account). 1953-1960, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Series III: Calf Sale Records, 1938-1963
  - Correspondence. 1940-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - First National Bank of Arizona: statements. 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Financial records and reports. 1938-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6-10)
  - Check stubs. 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Checks and deposit slips. 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series IV: Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association Records, 1932-1964
  - Yavapai Cattle Growers: by-laws, history, miscellaneous items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Yavapai Cattle Growers: reports, meetings. 1932-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Congress & Arizona Legislature: miscellaneous material. 1936-1960 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Arizona Cattle Growers' Association: convention. 1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association: constitution, membership lists, annual reports. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association: announcements. 1940-1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association: financial records. 1940-1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association: Manual of Range Plants. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Junior Yavapai Cattle Growers Association: Scrapbook. (Box 5)